<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NServiceBus on Meisinger Two</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/tags/nservicebus/</link><description>Recent content in NServiceBus on Meisinger Two</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://meisinger.github.io/tags/nservicebus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Head in the Clouds</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2010-08-21-head-in-the-clouds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2010-08-21-head-in-the-clouds/</guid><description>&lt;p>The past couple of months have been really fun as we have moved our whole product (lock stock and barrel) out into the Cloud.
Along the way I have learned a couple of things about the Cloud and myself that I think (clearly) is enlightening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Its weird, actually. It seems like I have been going through a renaissance of sorts lately with everything that has been going on.
Perhaps it has more to do with the epiphanies and &amp;ldquo;ah ha&amp;rdquo; moments as of late but in either case, plenty of topics to cover so let&amp;rsquo;s not waste any time.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NServiceBus - Fifteen Minutes...</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2009-11-10-nservicebus-fifteen-minutes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2009-11-10-nservicebus-fifteen-minutes/</guid><description>&lt;p>After downloading the assemblies I was ready to create my first sample application using NServiceBus.
From what I can tell, a lot of time and effort has gone into building the &lt;strong>NServiceBus.Host&lt;/strong> executable so if you plan on using it… you’re in luck,
there are plenty of examples out there on how to use it. If you don’t want to use it, however, get ready for some digging
(take a guess on which direction I went in). Hopefully this post will serve as a good example of how to handle things when you don’t want to use &lt;strong>NServiceBus.Host&lt;/strong>.
Time will tell…&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>