<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Meisinger Two</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/categories/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Meisinger Two</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://meisinger.github.io/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rounding Out The Year Like A Roller Coaster</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2013-05-15-rounding-out-the-year-like-a-roller-coaster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2013-05-15-rounding-out-the-year-like-a-roller-coaster/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my last post I state that I was starting over. As I wrote that post I never would have imagined that I would have the year like I did.
Sure, starting in the “ground” floor is a bummer but, you lace up the boot straps and meet the situation head on.
What I wasn’t expecting, however, were the ups and downs that I experienced through out the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With it being a little over a year since, things have improved. Most notably, the time I have been spending with my family have been very rewarding.
I have also found a good balance between family time, personal time and work. I am very fortunate to have a family who understand that I am passionate
about software development. And recently my “work life” has been improving. Unfortunately (depending on the perspective) the software developer in me
has been itching to do more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starting Over</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2012-02-14-starting-over/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2012-02-14-starting-over/</guid><description>&lt;p>Losing a job because you are not capable is something that I have always been able to handle gracefully.
I have never thought that I am owed continued employment if my skills and abilities were no longer serving the purpose of the company.
I even find it somewhat tolerable when the views of my employer and myself are no longer the same or differ too greatly.
For the first time, however, I have recently been in the position of losing a job due to financial reasons.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nothing lost but time</title><link>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2009-03-12-nothing-lost-but-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://meisinger.github.io/post/2009-03-12-nothing-lost-but-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a while since I last posted anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this hiatus I have been working on several things that have been really interesting.
Unfortunately none of which has been in the .Net world. Yup&amp;hellip; you guessed it, I have been off working in the Java world for the last year.
And while I kept up with the going&amp;rsquo;s on in the .Net world (or at least tried too),
there was never enough time to keep my head wrapped around the Java work while continuing to dive into my beloved .Net world.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>